You ought to go!
Keep an eye on him!
No, wait!
Damn!
Where the hell does he think he's going?
Shit.
I don't know if I can't believe it.
I don't know if I
can't believe it.
Meburu chisana oh my.
Kizuku yawai watashi Game ga yleba.
Nagai yume miru koro wa so aehen des.
I wanna always be with you!
I'm giving you everything I have.
You idiot!
What's your problem?
Well, what happened?
I lost him.
He Teleport off somewhere.
The system's supposed to
protect players inside the inns.
I thought if anywhere,
she'd be safe in here.
Damn it!
That robe was Griselda's.
That was Griselda's ghost.
She's come back to get revenge on us.
Think about it.
Only a ghost can PK
someone in a safe zone.
That wasn't a ghost.
Someone's using the system to kill.
That's the only way these murders
could have happened in a safe zone.
I know it.
I don't know what to think.
Was that black-robed
figure Griselda's ghost?
After seeing two people die mysteriously,
I'm starting to think it's possible.
No.
That definitely wasn't a ghost.
I'd bet my life on it.
Why would a ghost need a teleport crystal?
Teleport crystal. What is it?
Nah, it's nothing.
Here.
What is that for me?
Well, what do you think I'm doing?
Showing it off?
Are you going to take it or what?
Okay, thanks. Thank you.
Better eat it fast before it disappears.
Its durability is almost down to zero.
Oh, uh, right.
It's delicious.
When the heck do you find
time to pick this up?
I had a feeling we wouldn't
have time for lunch today.
So this morning I packed one for us.
Hurry up and eat it, okay?
Gotta hand it to you.
For a second in command of the
Knights of the Blood Oath, You rock.
Where'd you buy these, anyway?
I didn't. Huh?
I made it.
Yes, I can cook, so what?
Wow, I...
I don't even know what to say.
I mean, if you're looking for a second
career, you'd make a killing selling these.
Oh, should've been eating
instead of talking.
Are you crying?
No way!
That's right.
That's it!
What's it?
What did you just figure out?
I...
No, wait.
We never saw a thing.
We just thought we did, but
we were seeing something else.
I was right.
The game doesn't allow
killing inside a safe zone.
There's no weapon or system exploit.
Griselda
The only way I can be saved now.
Is if you forgive me.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Please forgive me, Griselda.
I swear.
I never thought this was going to happen.
You have to believe me.
Oh really!
What did you do to me?
Tell me, Schmidt.
Tell me what you did.
Tell me now.
Okay, okay.
The day we voted to sell the ring,
I looked at my belt pouch and there was
a crystal and a note with instructions.
Who were they from?
Who gave you them?
Grimlock, you're dead too?
Tell me.
I want to know who gave
you those instructions.
I don't know!
I swear I don't know!
The note said for me to bind
the crystal to Grisolda's room
at the inn she was staying at
so whoever it was could get in.
Then I had to put the crystal
in the guild's shared storage.
Then what?
That's all I did! I swear!
I didn't want her to die!
I didn't want to be part of that!
Please!
Believe me!
We recorded everything you said, Schmidt.
Wait, they're alive?
Yup, they're alive.
Both Caynz and Yorko.
Inside safe zones, a player's
HP doesn't deplete on its own.
But the durability of an object does.
Just like that sandwich you gave me.
What?
That day, the spear was
sticking out of Kynes' armor.
It wasn't draining his HP, though.
It was draining the
durability of his armor.
But then, his body didn't disintegrate.
It was… Yup. Just his armor. Nothing else.
And at the precise second when his
armor's durability expired, poof.
Caynz used a crystal to
teleport out of his armor.
Sure, it looks a lot like what happens
when a player dies in the game.
Only he didn't die.
Then what happened to Yorkel?
I bet the dagger was rigged
to her back the whole time.
She had it all planned out.
But we would have seen.
Only if she turned around, though.
Remember, she never turned her back to us.
Not even once.
She kept an eye on her equipment's
durability level while she was talking.
When it got down to zero,
all she had to do was act
like she was hit by a dagger,
thrown from outside the window.
Who was the person in the
black robe you chased?
It wasn't Grimlock, I'm
pretty sure of that.
But Caynz?
He and Yoriko were in it together.
They figured out how they could use
this method to fake their own deaths.
Getting people to think they were murdered
in a safe zone was a calculated twist.
Everything they did was
designed to draw out the
person behind Griselda's
murder and expose him.
The only way to find out
for sure was by faking
their deaths and creating
an illusionary Avenger.
And Schmidt was the person they had picked
for it, probably since the beginning.
Hey, you still have Yorko on
your friend list, don't you?
Right now she's in the field on floor 19.
It looks like she's on a small
hill, just outside of town. I see.
That's it then.
I guess they can handle it from here.
I mean, our job's pretty much
done now, wouldn't you say?
Mm-hmm.
You were recording?
So, that's how it is, huh?
You cared about what happened
to Griselda after all.
Of course we did, but you didn't betray
her because you hated her, did you?
No, I didn't hate her, honest.
I mean,
sure, I feel guilty getting
money for my part of it,
but the rare weapon I bought helped
me get into the Holy Dragon Alliance,
so...
Paralysis?
One down!
No way!
That's a hell of a catch.
A big shot from the Holy Dragon Alliance.
Laughing Coffin, the Murder Guild.
Alright, what game should
we play with these three?
Oh, I know! I know!
Let's play the one where
they have to kill each other
last one standing wins I
know it's your favorite,
but last time we did that
you killed the winner anyway.
Oh, come on You spoiled it.
It's no fun if they know they're gonna die
All right, let's get this show on the road
Huh?
Damn.
Looks like I made it just in time.
So, now what?
I got 30 players from
the assault team coming.
You guys want to stay and fight them?
Come on.
Nice to see you alive again, Yorko.
You won't believe me, but after it was
over, I was going to tell you the truth.
I am sorry we had to
trick you to help us out.
Kirito, thank you for saving me,
but how did you figure it out?
How did you know those
three would attack us here?
I didn't figure anything out.
I was acting on a hunch is all.
Hey, Yorko, Caynz, level with me.
You guys asked Grimlock to make the
spear and the knife, didn't you?
We did, but he was against
our plan from the beginning.
All he wanted was to let
Griselda rest in peace.
He did forge the weapons for us,
but only after we got down
on our knees and begged him.
Sorry, but he had a different
reason for not liking your plan.
Griselda had nothing to do with it.
He was worried faking PKs in a safe zone
was going to draw a lot of attention.
He didn't want to take the risk of
someone snooping around for answers.
We figured the whole thing
out about half an hour ago.
We ended up playing right into
Yoriko's hands, didn't we?
You know what?
I don't really mind. Yeah, me neither.
Hey, if you were in their guild,
and a super rare item like that
dropped, what would you have done?
Oh, I don't know.
I play solo.
Part of why I do is so I can
avoid situations like that.
In my guild, the one who
got the kill gets it.
Those are the rules we have to play by.
You know how in SAO, if
a player gets a drop,
no one knows unless
that person reports it?
Our way, no one can hoard stuff because
we worked out who gets what ahead of time.
Also,
the rules my guilt play by gives the concept
of marriage in this world real meaning.
Think about it.
If you marry, you have to
share your item storage.
If you're single,
you can hide whatever
you want, but, you know,
when you're married, you
can't hide it anymore.
I think sharing storage with the person
you're married to is wonderfully pragmatic.
At the same time, I think
it's also very romantic.
Hey. Yeah? What?
So, uh, how many times have
you been married, anyway?
Wait, I didn't mean it!
That didn't come out right!
You were talking about how it's
romantic and plastic and...
I did not say that, you ass!
What I said is it's
romantic and pragmatic.
For your information, the word
pragmatic means practical. My god.
You think marriage in SAO
is practical? Of course.
If you're married,
everything's out in the open,
you know, because of common storage.
What?
That's it.
Common storage.
Okay, say your spouse dies.
What happens to the items?
Item storage is shared, right?
So when one person dies,
what happens to their stuff?
If you're talking about Griselda and
Grimlock, hmm, if one of them died...
Everything would go to the
surviving spouse, right?
And if everything goes to the spouse,
then the ring in Griselda's storage...
...should be sitting in Grimlock's
storage, not the killer's.
It's been sitting there this whole time.
It was never stolen in the first place.
No, it was stolen.
It doesn't matter it's still there.
Grimlock was basically stealing it the
minute he put his plan into action.
It was Grimlock?
Then those were his instructions.
And he killed Griselda, too.
No, I doubt he was the one
who actually killed her.
Although, I'm pretty sure he went and found
himself a red player to do it for him.
My God.
But then if he really did have her killed,
why would he go to all that
trouble just to help us out?
You explained your plan to
him in detail, didn't you?
Your plan was the perfect
chance for him to bury
the ring incident and any
witnesses once and for all.
All he'd have to do is
sit back and wait for you,
Schmidt, and Caynz to get together.
You'd be sitting ducks.
That's it.
That's why.
They knew we'd be here
because he hired them.
Yeah.
My guess is it was probably the same
bunch he hired to kill Griselda.
Oh my god.
Found him.
If you want to know more,
you can ask the man yourself.
Hello.
Long time no see, comrades.
I can't believe it.
Did you...
did you really plan this?
How could you, Grimlock? Answer me!
Why did you kill Griselda?
Was it the money?
Was the money so important to you
that you'd kill your own wife for it?
Money?
Did you say money?
It wasn't for the money.
I had to.
No matter what, I had to kill her
while we were stuck in this world.
I had to kill her while
she was still my wife.
And because she was also
my wife in the real world.
In a way, she was the perfect wife. Ideal.
So pretty, so submissive.
The whole time we were together,
we never had a single fight.
But when we were trapped in
here, in this world, she changed.
In here, I was the one who was afraid,
terrified of playing this death game.
But she looked so much happier here, more
alive than she ever did in the real world.
There was nothing I could do about it.
She changed.
The Yuuki I loved was gone.
Gone but then I realized I didn't
have to live with the way she was.
Murder is part of this game.
If I couldn't have the Yuuki I loved
back, I'd settle for the memory of her.
And who could blame me?
That's why you did it.
That's the reason you killed your wife.
It's reason enough.
And someday you'll understand too.
Once you've found love, believe me.
You'll do anything to keep it.
You're wrong, Grimlock!
You've got it all wrong!
You didn't love Griselda.
That's not what you felt.
You stopped loving her when you
became selfish and possessive.
Kirito, we appreciate your help.
But I think this is our
problem to deal with now.
Okay.
Hey.
Say it was you, and you married someone.
And later on, you found out she had
a side tour you didn't know about.
How would you feel?
I guess that I was lucky.
Because,
I mean, if you marry someone,
that means you already like whatever
you know about them, doesn't it?
And if you discovered
something you didn't know
about them before and fell
in love with that too,
then that would be awesome.
Right, good answer.
Anyway, I'm hungry after all this.
I didn't really get to finish my dinner.
Oh, yeah, he didn't.
We should get back to work tomorrow.
We've been off the front
lines for two days.
Yeah, I was hoping to have this floor
totally cleared by the end of this week.
Now what?
Hey, Kirito.
Do you want to friend me?
It's kind of silly not to.
It's convenient.
We are in the same assault team after all.
But I'm a solo player.
Hey, I didn't say you had
to form a party with me.
You should try to make some
friends while you're here.
Yeah, I don't know.
It's not that I don't want...
Hey!
Think about it while we eat.
No pressure.
Come on, let's go back and
find a good restaurant.
Uh, okay.
I'm not even going to be a little bit.
I'll be strong again.
I'll be
strong
again.
The temperature of the heart.